Register of the Petr Berngardovich Struve papers, 1890-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
- FILES CREATED AS EDITOR AND CONTRIBUTOR, 1914-1934 (Boxes 24-37)
  - Vozrozhdenie (Paris), 1917-1928
    - Correspondence
      - Thomas, Albert, 1926 (Box-folder 31: 95)
      - Timrot, A., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 96)
      - Tishchenko, E., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 97)
      - Tolmachev, Iurii I., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 98)
      - Tomara (Dombrovskii), M., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 99)
      - Tret'iakov, Lev, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 100)
      - Trubetskoi, S. E., 1925, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 101)
      - Tsakoni, A., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 102)
      - Tsitovich, A., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 103)
      - Tuberozov, A., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 104)
      - Unger, F., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 1)
      - Union Francaise d'Aide aux Russes, 1926 (Box-folder 32: 2)
      - Unmut, A., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 3)
      - Ushakov, M., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 4)
      - Valitskii, I. V., 1925 (Box-folder 32: 5)
      - Varshavskii, S. I., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 32: 6)
      - Vasil'ev, Nikolai, 1927 (Box-folder 32: 7)
      - Vasil'ev, Vladimir, 1927 (Box-folder 32: 8)
      - Vasnetsov, M., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 9)
      - Vazhentsev, Stepan, 1927 (Box-folder 32: 10)
      - Veselovskii, N., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 11)
      - Viaz'mitinov, V. E., 1926 (Box-folder 32: 12)
      - Vil'chkovskii, Kirill, 1927 (Box-folder 32: 13)
      - Vinogradov, N., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 32: 14)
      - Vitka, Avgust K., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 15)
      - Vitt, A. K., 1925 (Box-folder 32: 16)
      - Vladimirov, Evgenii, 1926 (Box-folder 32: 17)
      - Voinov, Igor, 1927 (Box-folder 32: 18)
      - Voitsekhovskii, S., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 19)
      - Volkonskaia, S., 1928 (Box-folder 32: 20)
      - Volkov, Mikhail S., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 21)
      - Vorob'ev, Nikolai, 1925 (Box-folder 32: 22)
      - Voronchenko, V. P., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 23)
      - Voronin, S., 1925 (Box-folder 32: 24)
      - Vorotynskii, Dmitrii, 1925 (Box-folder 32: 25)
      - Voskresenskii, Nikolai, 1927 (Box-folder 32: 26)
      - Voznesenskii, A., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 27)
      - Vrublevskii, Aron, undated (Box-folder 32: 28)
      - Vyrubov, N., 1926 (Box-folder 32: 29)
      - Z., undated (Box-folder 32: 30)
      - Zavalishin, Boris, 1927 (Box-folder 32: 31)
      - Zelenskii, 1926 (Box-folder 32: 32)
      - Zhebulov, S., 1925 (Box-folder 32: 33)
      - Zhilinskii, N. P., undated (Box-folder 32: 34)
      - Zhirov, P. M., 1926 (Box-folder 32: 35)
      - Zhoravovich, Konstantin, 1925 (Box-folder 32: 36)
      - Zil'berbert, I. E., 1925 (Box-folder 32: 37)
      - Zon, Natalia von, 1927 (Box-folder 32: 38)
      - Zozulevskii, S., 1926 (Box-folder 32: 39)
      - Zurov, L., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 32: 40)
      - Zvezdochkin, Anisim G., 1927 (Box-folder 32: 41)
    - Articles submitted for publication
      - Anonymous authors
        - "Bor'ba s bol'shevikami i prizrak staroi Rossii," typescript (Box-folder 32: 42)
        - "Chto soobshchil Operput," typescript (Box-folder 32: 43)
        - "Delo 48," galley proof (Box-folder 32: 44)
        - "Dokument," typescript (Box-folder 32: 45)
        - "Donesenie Vysokopreosveshchennomu ..." (Box-folder 32: 46)
        - Essay re obnovlen'chestvo movement in Russian Church received from the Soviet Union, holograph (Box-folder 32: 47)
        - "Gallipoli," typescript (Box-folder 32: 48)
        - "Indus, pobyvavshii na Solovkakh," typescript (Box-folder 32: 49)
        - "Lzheimennaia tserkov v SSSR," typescript (Box-folder 32: 50)
        - "Mechtaniia o Pan-Europe," typescript (Box-folder 32: 51)
        - "Na dal'nem vostoke - khronika nashei zhizni," typescript (Box-folder 32: 52)
        - "Na doklade G.A. Aleksinskago," typescript (Box-folder 32: 53)
        - Obituary of S. P. Shlikevich, typescript (Box-folder 32: 54)
        - "Otvet Petru Berngardovichu Struve," holograph (Box-folder 32: 55)
        - "Pesn' dvorianskogo polka," typescript (Box-folder 32: 56)
        - "Pis'mo iz Rossii, ianvar'," holograph, 1927 (Box-folder 32: 57)
        - Political caricature, drawing, and holograph text (Box-folder 32: 58)
        - "Pol'skaia pechat' o vospominaniiakh S. D., Sazonova," typescript (Box-folder 32: 59)
        - "Raskol v Varshavskoi Demokraticheskoi Gruppe," typescript (Box-folder 32: 60)
        - "Revoliutsiia - vospominaniia o fevral'skoi revoliutsii goda," typescript, 1917 (Box-folder 32: 61)
        - "Russkoe Istoricheskoe Obshchestvo," holograph (Box-folder 32: 62)
        - "Sem' raz primer', potom otrezh," typescript (Box-folder 32: 63)
        - "S'ezd slavianskikh istorikov v Varshave," typescript (Box-folder 32: 64)
        - "Soiuz sovetov," holograph (Box-folder 32: 65)
        - "Soveshchanie predstavitelei novogo molodogo pokoleniia v Parizhe v avguste mesiatse goda," typescript, 1926 (Box-folder 32: 66)
        - "Spravka o Shankhaiskoi Lige dlia bor'by s III Internatsionalom," typescript (Box-folder 32: 67)
        - "Streiflichter aus dem sowjetrussischen Arbeiterleben," typescript (Box-folder 32: 68)
        - "Stroiteli Rossii," typescript (Box-folder 32: 69)
        - "Tezisy doklada P. N. Miliukova o 'Evraziistve'," typescript (Box-folder 32: 70)
        - Untitled, holograph (Box-folder 32: 71)
        - "Vneshniia politika Chekhoslovakii," typescript (Box-folder 32: 72)
        - "Vneshniaia torgovlia SSSR," typescript (Box-folder 32: 73)
      - A. N., "Podkarpatskaia Rus' - interpelliatsiia v dele pravoslaviia," holograph (Box-folder 32: 74)
      - Afanas'ev, Ivan E. (Putnik), "Pis'ma so storony," holograph (Box-folder 32: 75)
      - Aikanov, M., "Mir i ob'edinenie dlia bor'by i...bor'ba ..." (Box-folder 32: 76)
      - Akaemov, N. F., "Varshavskii sobor," holograph (Box-folder 32: 77)
      - Aleksandrov, A., "Nemetskii patriot o bol'shevikakh i ikh mezhdunarodnom polozhenii," holograph (Box-folder 32: 78)
      - Aleksandrov, P., "Razval," typescript (Box-folder 32: 79)
      - Almaz, "Pis'ma iz Ispanii - ispanskaia promyshlennost' i pravitel'stvennye tarify," holograph (Box-folder 32: 80)
      - Amfiteatrov, Aleksandr, holograph
        - "Mysli o russkoi vere" (Box-folder 32: 81)
        - "O mudrenykh i strashnykh slovakh" (Box-folder 32: 82)
      - Andreev, V. K.
        - Letter to the editor (Box-folder 32: 83)
        - "K russkim ludiam, iskrenno liubiashchim svoiu rodinu," holograph (Box-folder 32: 84)
      - Anichkova, S. (Baroness S. Taube), "Mirno spiashchii - kartinki iz zhizni Sovetskoi Rossi," typescript (Box-folder 32: 85)
      - Antonov, Konstantin A., holograph
        - "Otkrytoe pis'mo glavnomu redaktoru" (Box-folder 32: 86)
        - "Rossiia vozroditsia" (Box-folder 32: 87)
      - Ardennskii, V., holograph
        - "Blestiashchii publitsist s tumannoi filosofiei" (Box-folder 32: 88)
        - "Na Valaame" (Box-folder 32: 89)
      - Arsen'ev, N. S., review of the lecture, "O russkoi narodnoi stikhii i o tserkvi," holograph (Box-folder 32: 90)
      - Arsen'ev, P., "To, chto mozhet byt' i to, chto budet. stsenki budushchego," typescript (Box-folder 32: 91)
      - B. V., untitled article about the Russian emigration, holograph, 1925 October 4 (Box-folder 33: 1)
      - Baikov, B.
        - "Pis'ma iz Ameriki - fakty russkoi deistvitel' nosti," holograph and typescript (Box-folder 33: 2)
        - "Pis'ma iz Ameriki - k evreiskoi kolonizatsii v Rossii," holograph and typescript (Box-folder 33: 3)
        - "Pis'ma iz Ameriki - nekotorye itogi deiatel'nosti A. Kerenskogo v Amerike," typescript (Box-folder 33: 4)
        - "Pis'mo iz Ameriki," holograph (Box-folder 33: 5)
        - "Pis'mo iz Ameriki - iavnyi proval bol'shevikov v russkoi kolonii. Neudachnaia popytka ikh agitatsii v amerikanskoi presse," typescript (Box-folder 33: 6)
      - Bakh, untitled essay on materialism, typescript (Box-folder 33: 7)
      - Balkashin, T. A., "Paskha v Nitstse," holograph (Box-folder 33: 8)
      - Bartalovskii, Ia., "Koe-chto o Dal'nem Vostoke," holograph (Box-folder 33: 9)
      - Belov, Aleksandr
        - "Polozhenie truda v Sovetskoi Rossii," holograph (Box-folder 33: 10)
        - "Dve Evropy - posviashchiaetsia V. V. Shul'ginu" (Box-folder 33: 11)
        - "Kitai v bezumii" (Box-folder 33: 12)
        - "Russkaia problema vo frantsuzkoi literature" (Box-folder 33: 13)
      - "Bezpartiinyi," "Russkaia zhizn' v Belgrade--zaboty o nastoiashchem," typescript (Box-folder 33: 14)
      - Bigaev, N., "Mozgami k kazachestvu," holograph (Box-folder 33: 15)
      - Bobrinskoi, Aleksei, translation of an article by Sir Sidney Law, Daily Mail, "Nasha oslabevshaia palata obshchin," holograph, 1926 February 2 (Box-folder 33: 16)
      - Bogdanovich, V., "Rech v pol'skom senate, 23-go iiulia, 1924," typescript (Box-folder 33: 17)
      - Boidereva, Liubov, "Zametki o Kitae," typescript (Box-folder 33: 18)
      - Borman, A. (Piterskii), "Russkoe delo," galley proof (Box-folder 33: 19)
      - Borodaevsky, M., "K liubiashchim rodinu," holograph (Box-folder 33: 20)
      - Budakhin, Boris, "Otkrytoe pis'mo Mitropolitu Evlogiiu," holograph (Box-folder 33: 21)
      - Budanov, I., "Kazaki i Zarubezhnyi S'ezd," holograph (Box-folder 33: 22)
      - Burnakin, A. A., reports from Constantinople, holograph, 1926 December (Box-folder 33: 23)
      - Byval'kevich, P., holograph
        - "50-letnii iubilei Novago Vremeni" (Box-folder 33: 24)
        - "Shag trezvoi pol'skoi politiki" (Box-folder 33: 25)
      - "Byvshii chlen R.D.O.", "Eshche o novoi taktike," holograph and typescript (Box-folder 33: 26)
      - Chashnikov, "Puti bor'by," typescript (Box-folder 33: 27)
      - Chelishchev, V. N., "Iz belgradskoi pechati - sud'by pravoslavnoi tserkvi v Pol'she i Prikarpatskoi Rusi," holograph (Box-folder 33: 28)
      - Cheprianskii, V., "Svetloi pamiati Zheni Fredrikh," holograph (Box-folder 33: 29)
      - Cheremisinov, V., "Pamiati Generala A. N. Selivanova," holograph (Box-folder 33: 30)
      - Chernosvitova, M. V., holograph
        - "Razgovory vokrug Vozrozhdeniia i ego redaktora" (Box-folder 33: 31)
        - "Starye liude" (Box-folder 33: 32)
      - Chernov, Sergei, "Legendy nashikh dnei," holograph (Box-folder 33: 33)
      - Chirikov, Evgenii, "O 'shkure neubitogo medvedia," holograph (Box-folder 33: 34)
      - Chubov, A., "Otkliki chitatelia," holograph (Box-folder 33: 35)
      - Danilov, N., "Poezdka v Vil'no," holograph (Box-folder 33: 36)
      - Daoin, typescripts
        - "Khoziaistvennye bolezni Iaponii - novyi faktor v ..." (Box-folder 33: 37)
        - "Obyski v Pekine" (Box-folder 33: 38)
        - "Pod luchami voskhodiashchego solntsa" (Box-folder 33: 39)
        - "Polozhenie v Kitae - vydvizhenie Chzhan-Kai-Shi" (Box-folder 33: 40)
        - "Provalivsheesia vozstanie krasnykh v Kharbine" (Box-folder 33: 41)
        - "Russkii parad v Shankhae" (Box-folder 33: 42)
        - "S Dal'nego Vostoka" (Box-folder 33: 43)
        - "Sovetizatsiia podnebesnoi revoliutsii" (Box-folder 33: 44)
        - "Zapravila sovetskoi politiki v Kitae - Madame i Monsieur Loshevich" (Box-folder 33: 45)
      - Desiatov, A., untitled essay on the history of Jews in Russia, holograph (Box-folder 33: 46)
      - Diakov, A. A.
        - "Golos iz tumannoi dali," holograph (Box-folder 33: 47)
        - Open letter to the editor, 1925 (Box-folder 33: 48)
      - Diufur, V., typescript
        - "Na zare franko-russkogo soiuza" (Box-folder 33: 49)
        - "Staryi Peterburg" (Box-folder 33: 50)
      - Dolinskii, N. V., holograph
        - "Ekho predvoennoi i sledvoennoi afer" (Box-folder 33: 51)
        - "Pamiati uchitelia" (Box-folder 33: 52)
      - Drizo, caricature (Box-folder 33: 53)
      - Dubasova, Irina, "V sviazi s sobytiiami v Anglii," holograph (Box-folder 33: 54)
      - Dukhin, I., "Prazdnovanie chekhami godovshchiny russkoi revoliutsii," holograph (Box-folder 33: 55)
      - Dzanti, D., "Osetinskoe Natsional'noe Ob'edinenie," holograph (Box-folder 33: 56)
      - E---on (?), N., "Iz Avstrii," holograph (Box-folder 33: 57)
      - Eiler, Aleksandr A., "25-letnii iubilei Slavianskogo Obshchestva v Bolgarii," typescript (Box-folder 33: 58)
      - Elika (M. Kadenko), "Ne fel'eton," holograph (Box-folder 33: 59)
      - Epanchin, General N. A., "Krestovui pokhod 1877-1878," holograph (Box-folder 33: 60)
        Includes correspondence of author with P. B. Struve.
      - Erdman, A., open letter to Prime Minister LLoyd George, mimeograph (Box-folder 33: 61)
      - Eristov, M. P, "Bogosluzhenie v Shavile," holograph (Box-folder 33: 62)
      - Eropkin, A., "Na Zarubezhnom S'ezde v Parizhe - otchet izbirateliam," holograph (Box-folder 33: 63)
      - Ertsdorf-Kupfer, M. von, "Mir poslezavtra: restavratsiia natsional'noi Rossi," holograph (Box-folder 33: 64)
      - Evdokimov, E., response to E. Sablin's letter of June 5, 1927, holograph (Box-folder 33: 65)
      - Ezerskii, N., "Khristianskaia deistvennost', kak ocherednaia zadacha," typescript and holograph (Box-folder 33: 66)
      - F., "'Shveik'," holograph (Box-folder 33: 67)
      - Fedorov, Nikolai, "Iugoslavianskaia tetrad'," holograph (Box-folder 33: 68)
      - Fenin, A. I.
        - "Ekonomicheskoe razvitie i polozhenie Rossii do pervoi mirovoi voiny," holograph (Box-folder 33: 69-70)
        - "Sostoianie zheleznodorozhnogo transporta v Sovetskoi Rossii," holograph (Box-folder 34: 1)
        - "Sozidatel'nyi protsess v sovetskoi promyshlennosti," typescript (Box-folder 34: 2)
      - Ferguson, Barbara, "Psikhologicheskii etiud," holograph (Box-folder 34: 3)
      - Filimonov, A., "Neobkhodimaia iuridocheskaia spravka po tserkovnomu voprosu," holograph (Box-folder 34: 4)
      - Frank, Rikhard, text of N. I. Korchak-Kotovich's lecture "Velikaia nedelimaia edinaia Rossiia i okrainnye gosudarstva," holograph (Box-folder 34: 5)
      - Gagilev, K., holograph
        - Autobiographical essay, 1927 (Box-folder 34: 6)
        - "V potokakh zhizni - psikhologicheskie siluety" (Box-folder 34: 7)
      - Galitskii, Roman, "Graf Andrei Sheptytskii Mitropolit Evlogii," holograph (Box-folder 34: 8)
      - Gaug, Ekaterina, "Pis'mo k materiam," holograph (Box-folder 34: 9)
      - Gefding, V., "Real'nost' biudzheta SSSR," typescript (Box-folder 34: 10)
      - Gerua, B., "Nam pishut iz Londona," holograph (Box-folder 34: 11)
      - Girs, Aleksei, "Pamiati Imperatora Nikolaia II," holograph (Box-folder 34: 12)
      - Girs, M. N., "Vypiska iz dnevnika Generala A. N. Zamiatina," holograph (Box-folder 34: 13)
      - Gomichkov, Vladimir, "Karpatorossy o vystuplenii Abbata Kene," holograph (Box-folder 34: 14)
      - Grabbe, D. M., untitled article about the land question, typescript (Box-folder 34: 15)
      - Grigorov, K., "Iz zhizni russkoi kolonii v Bel'gii," holograph (Box-folder 34: 16)
      - Grimm, D., "Beloe dvizhenie - ego vnutrennii smysl i znachenie," holograph (Box-folder 34: 17)
      - Grimm, M., "Slavnoe porazhenie'," holograph (Box-folder 34: 18)
      - Gurko, V. I.
        - "Liberal'nyi konservatizm," holograph (Box-folder 34: 19)
        - "Liubov' k rodine," holograph (Box-folder 34: 20)
        - "Soznatel'noe izvrashchenie istiny ili nevezhestvo," typescript (Box-folder 34: 21)
      - Gusliar-Severianin, "Pizyv," "Boevaia trevoga," clipping (Box-folder 34: 22)
      - Gutovskii, N., "Otzvuki zarubezhnogo s'ezda v Montarzhi," holograph (Box-folder 34: 23)
      - Iablonovskii, Aleksandr, holograph
        - "Pis'mo Shvartsborda" (Box-folder 34: 24)
        - "Vopros akademicheskii" (Box-folder 34: 25)
        - "Vsadnik bez golovy" (Box-folder 34: 26)
      - Iakobin, I., untitled essay on Russians in exile, holograph (Box-folder 34: 27)
      - Ionov, E., "Russkie v Estonii - kontrasty," holograph (Box-folder 34: 28)
      - Iu., A., "Zamiranie ili smert'," typescript (Box-folder 34: 29)
      - Iur'ev, "Pokhorony Korolevy Luizy," holograph (Box-folder 34: 30)
      - Iurshevskii, L., untitled paper and letter, typescript (Box-folder 34: 31)
      - Ivanov, Vsevolod, "Pis'mo iz Kitaia," typescript (Box-folder 34: 32)
      - "Junior," "Finliandiia i zarubezhnyi s'ezd - pis'mo iz Gel'singforsa," typescript (Box-folder 34: 33)
      - Kasatkin-Rostovskii, Fedor, "Kolokol. Posviashchaetsia zarubezhonomu s'ezdu," holograph (Box-folder 34: 34)
      - Kasr-Shirin, "Po povodu s'ezda," typescript (Box-folder 34: 35)
      - Khir'iakov, A., "Fal'shivyi vitamin," typescript (Box-folder 34: 36)
      - Kirillov, Aleksandr, "Prokliatie bol'shevikam - pis'mo sibiraika," holograph (Box-folder 34: 37)
      - Kobiakov, D. (?), "Vtoroe zaniatie Kieva bol'shevikami," typescript (Box-folder 34: 38)
      - Komitet Deistviia Glavnogo Ob'edineniia Russkoi Emigrantskoi Molodezhi pri S.O.M., typescript resolution (Box-folder 34: 39)
      - Koptev, Aleksei, "V chem prichina?," holograph (Box-folder 34: 40)
      - Krasnov, P. N.
        - Response to K. Popov's Vospominaniia kavkazskogo grenadera, typescript (Box-folder 34: 41)
        - "Sroki voennoi sluzhby," holograph (Box-folder 34: 42)
      - Krestianskii Federatuvnyi Sovet Ukrainy, Dona (Box-folder 34: 43)
      - Kubani, Kavkaza, Sibiri i Povolzh'ia, typescript summary
      - Krivosheev, A., "Chto vy molchite?," holograph (Box-folder 34: 44)
      - Kulakovskii, S., review of three of F. F. Zelinskii's books, typescript (Box-folder 34: 45)
      - Kurdiumov, M. (M. A. Kallash), holograph
        - "Literaturnoe sinema" (Box-folder 34: 46)
        - "Narod Tolstogo i Russkaia Reviutsiia" (Box-folder 34: 47)
        - "Svoia initsiiativa" (Box-folder 34: 48)
      - Ladyzhenskii, V., "Dolzhno pomoch," holograph (Box-folder 34: 49)
      - Lavda, Mikhail, holograph
        - "Dva lageria" (Box-folder 34: 50)
        - "Malen'kaia popravka" (Box-folder 34: 51)
        - "Perepechatka vospreshchaetsia" (Box-folder 34: 52)
        - "Shti moldavaneshti?" (Box-folder 34: 53)
        - "Takt" (Box-folder 34: 54)
        - "Trudnye gody" (Box-folder 34: 55)
        - "Zabavnyi intsident" (Box-folder 34: 56)
      - Lavrov, L., "K zarubezhnomu s'ezdu," holograph (Box-folder 34: 57)
      - Lazarevskii, Boris, "Velikii Kniaz Konstantin Konstantinovich," typescript (Box-folder 34: 58)
      - Levitskii, Valerii, holograph
        - Open letters to the editor, 1925 (Box-folder 34: 59)
        - "V Sovetskoi Derevne" (Box-folder 34: 60)
      - Lisanovich, M. "Treshchina posle s"ezda," typescript (Box-folder 34: 61)
      - Liubimov, Lev
        - "Na nankete rossiiskago tsentral'nago ob"edineniia" (Box-folder 34: 62)
        - "Ob evraziistve," holograph (Box-folder 34: 63)
      - Luchov, N., holograph
        - "Famil'nyi al'bom. Kartinki proshlogo" (Box-folder 34: 64)
        - "65-aia godovshchina osvobozhdeniia krest'ian" (Box-folder 34: 65)
      - Lukash, Ivan, "Politicheskoe sobranie v Biiankure," galley proof (Box-folder 34: 66)
      - L'vova, A., "Chto my dolzhny poniat'," holograph (Box-folder 34: 67)
      - Maevskii, Vladislav A., "Korol' Aleksandr," holograph (Box-folder 34: 68)
      - Maksheev, N. A., holograph
        - "Emigratsionnaia opastnost'" (Box-folder 35: 1)
        - "Estoniia - dela tserkovnyia" (Box-folder 35: 2)
        - "Gorod polotnianyi - k 106 godovshchine Mikhailovskogo Artilleriiskogo Uchilishcha" (Box-folder 35: 3)
        - "Universitet v Tartu" (Box-folder 35: 4)
        - "Vysylka russkikh emigrantov. Goneniia na 'monarkhistov'" (Box-folder 35: 5)
      - Maksimovich, E., "Strastnaia Subbota," holograph (Box-folder 35: 6)
      - Marchenko, M. K., holograph
        - "Domoroshchennyi russkii vol'terianets XIX veka" (Box-folder 35: 7)
        - Untitled fragment (Box-folder 35: 8)
      - Massa, Luigi, "Korni rabochei oppozitsii v SSSR," typescript (Box-folder 35: 9)
      - "Mestnyi," "Russkii khram v Kolombei," typescript (Box-folder 35: 10)
      - Miller, Evgenii K., introductory statement at the opening session of the lecture series "Lektsii o Rossii," typescript, 1926 August 21 (Box-folder 35: 11)
      - Miloradovich, Mikhail, "K zadacham zarubezhnogo s'ezda," holograph (Box-folder 35: 12)
      - "Mladshii," "Razmyshleniia o s'ezde," typescript (Box-folder 35: 13)
      - Mosheva, G., untitled paper, holograph, 1927 (Box-folder 35: 14)
      - N., "Otkrytoe pis'mo P. N. Miliukovu,", 1927 February 3 (Box-folder 35: 15)
      - N. N., open letter to P. B. Struve, undated (Box-folder 35: 16)
      - Nelidin, A., "Segodnia," holograph (Box-folder 35: 17)
      - Nikanorov, I. V.
        - "Kanonicheskii urok," holograph (Box-folder 35: 18)
        - "Neozhidannye vstrechi," holograph (Box-folder 35: 19)
        - "Otvet A.N. Krupenskomu," galley proof (Box-folder 35: 20)
        - "Posledniaia cherta," holograph (Box-folder 35: 21)
        - "Provokatsionnoe deistvo," holograph (Box-folder 35: 22)
        - Response to "Sozvuchiia Novogo Zaveta," holograph (Box-folder 35: 23)
        - "Rozhdenie Antikhrista," holograph (Box-folder 35: 24)
        - "Sekuliarizatsiia," holograph (Box-folder 35: 25)
        - "To, chego ne bylo," holograph (Box-folder 35: 26)
        - "Ukazanie," holograph (Box-folder 35: 27)
      - Nikashin, P., holograph
        - "Katolitsism i Rossiia" (Box-folder 35: 28)
        - "Zhorzh Zand i Shopen" (Box-folder 35: 29)
      - Nikitin, A., "Zapiski partizana," typescript (Box-folder 35: 30)
      - Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke, "Velikii Kniaz' russkim liudiam," typescript (Box-folder 35: 31)
      - Nikolaev, G., holograph
        - "Russkie v Iugoslavii" (Box-folder 35: 32)
        - "Vesti iz Iugoslavii--krizis parlamentarizma" (Box-folder 35: 33)
      - Nikolaeva, Aleksandra, "Skaz o trekh veshchikh ptitsakh," typescript (Box-folder 35: 34)
      - Nikolich, Georgii, "U Generala Vrangelia," typescript draft and clipping (Box-folder 35: 35)
      - Novikov, F., "P. V. Ivanushkin," holograph (Box-folder 35: 36)
      - Novikov, V. N., translation of "Khartiia truda, opublikovannaia Velikim Fashistskim Sovetom 21-go aprelia goda v Rime," typescript, 1927 (Box-folder 35: 37)
      - O. N., "Real'naia politika" (Box-folder 35: 38)
      - O--n, N. E., "Arest sovetskogo diplomata - nam pishut iz veny," holograph (Box-folder 35: 39)
      - O--v, "Avos'," typescript (Box-folder 35: 40)
      - Oblaginin, N., untitled paper on Borodin's trail in Tyrnov, holograph (Box-folder 35: 41)
      - Obolenskii, N., report on discussions with Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich, typescript (Box-folder 35: 42)
      - Obukhov, I., "Russkim chlenam Partii VKP(B)," typescript (Box-folder 35: 43)
      - Ognev, I., "Razocharovannyi respublikanets," holograph (Box-folder 35: 44)
      - Orekhov, V., "Molodaia Rossii," typescript (Box-folder 35: 45)
      - Panas, I. O., typescripts
        - "Ivan Grigor'evich Naumovich - prosvetitel' Galitskoi Rusi" (Box-folder 35: 46)
        - "K prebyvaniiu Generala M. G. Cherniaeva v Prage v g 1877" (Box-folder 35: 47)
      - Parago, "Sovchinovnik osobogo naznachenii - noveishaia evoliutsiia Ustrialova," typescript (Box-folder 35: 48)
      - Pastukhov, N.L., untitled essay (Box-folder 35: 49)
      - "Patriot," untitled paper on the reports presented in New York on March 13, 1927 in memory of Tsar Nicholas and his family, typescript (Box-folder 35: 50)
      - Pervukhin, M. K., typescripts
        - "Dura lex - ot sobstvennogo rimskago korresondenta Vozrozhdeniia" (Box-folder 35: 51)
        - "Protsess Tsaniboni, Kapello i Kompaniia" (Box-folder 35: 52)
        - "S togo berega" (Box-folder 35: 53)
        - "Tsvetisty kust" (Box-folder 35: 54)
      - Petrishchev, A., et al, "Vozmozhno i neobkhodimo pereselenie v Kanadu," holograph and typescript (Box-folder 35: 55)
      - Pilenko, A., typescript
        - "Kitaiskie sobytiia" (Box-folder 35: 56)
        - "Pis'mo iz Parizha" (Box-folder 35: 57)
        - "Tochki zreniia" (Box-folder 35: 58)
      - Pimkovskii, Karnelii D., "Pesn' gusliara - iz novykh bylin," holograph (Box-folder 35: 59)